

BRANDON BEST

bbest.dev@gmail.com | (780) 977-9925 | brandonbest.ca/ 11441 Ellerslie Rd SW, Edmonton, AB T6W 1S9

Professional Summary

Blended experience of exposure to software development in both a professional and entrepreneurial setting. Attained self-developed skills outside of academic path include UI/UX design and product management. Utilizes knowledge from academic background of computing science and mathematics and aforementioned attained skills to bring a unique perspective to development teams.

EDUCATION

University of Alberta September 2013 – August 2019

Bachelor of Science: Computing Science

Software Product Management, UofA (via Coursera) October 2019 –

December 2019

Bachelor of Science: Computing Science

QUALITIES

- Collaborative team environment
- Entrepreneurial drive and work ethic
- Fast learner and enjoys expanding knowledge.
- Passion for technology
- Accountable and results driven

SKILLS

- Java, Python, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and TypeScript
- React, Angular, Spring Framework, Google Firebase, and Node.js
- NoSQL (Firestore) and SQL Databases (Oracle, Postgres, Firebase Realtime Database).
- Mobile App Development (Android & Xamarin)
- UI/UX prototyping using Figma.
- Machine learning techniques and concepts.

System Analyst | Haemonetics Canada Ltd. - Edmonton, AB 05/2019 - PRESENT

WORK HISTORY

- Software developer for our Donor Management System software which plasma donation clinics use to manage the operation.
- Semi-agile work environment to experience how teams try to improve their work style as they evolved it.
- Product is a Java server project using tools like Spring Framework and Oracle SQL Database. Got experience working on a very complex enterprise software product which exposed me to advanced software architecture and software quality standards for enterprises and the healthcare industry.

Technical Systems Analyst | Royal Bank of Canada – Toronto, ON 08/2017 – 05/2019

- Worked on the frontend of an internal tool for portfolio managers. Frontend was done in Angular. Great first time exposure to modern web development technologies for enterprise software.
- Also worked on backend day one data loading processes to populate the application database for launch. This was taking current information from internal spreadsheets and loading it into the Oracle SQL database using Apache POI (Java).
 Experience dealing with lots of business rules in a totally new domain so was a great challenge to rapidly increase my knowledge on a new problem space.

Founder | Xpertz Software Corp. (more info on website) 05/2018 - 10/2019

- Enterprise SaaS platform for skill management and to analyze collaborative efforts within large organizations. First real entrepreneurial experience doing product discovery and development.
- Built a Slack Bot that allowed people to display skills in Slack and find others to collaborate with by searching based on skill.
 Learned how to ideate and develop a new product for launch, and as well using cloud tools for a product.
- Built Slack Bot using Firebase Functions (Google Cloud Functions) and Realtime Database (NoSQL) all in JavaScript.

VP Technology | NeurAlbertaTech (more info on website) 02/2019 – 04/2019

- Lead the club in creating an idea for a project to submit to the NeuroTechX student club competition. We decided on a 2D shooter game controlled by alpha brain waves using a Muse.
- Help organize the team structure and work process as well contribute to programming some of the game visuals.

ACTIVITIES